NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files. 6174/016
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Officers Meeting 11/1/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  Agenda; calculator wheel for determining annual out-of-pocket costs for prescriptions for Medicare beneficiaries; memo revising reimbursement process for meals by officers when travelling or entertaining, October 24; materials re 2006 Representative Assembly; correspondence between retired NYSUT president Tom Hobart and Organization of NYSUT Staff Retirees, May-October 2005; Retiree Leadership Handbook; sketches for Sandra Feldman Memorial Garden; newspaper clipping re dedication of annual Strides Against Breast Cancer Walk to Sandra Feldman
- Officers Meeting 9/21/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  Agenda; Peer Intervention Program Year 17 Final Report; letter from League of Women Voters of New York State Education Foundation, requesting $20,000 to expand Students Inside Albany program, June 23, 2005,with cover memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin noting that NYSUT had given $10,000, September 9; NYSUT's 2005 Retire Services Survey Results; memo re release time for staff participating in Hurricane Katrina relief efforts, September 19
- Officers Meeting 9/7/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  Agenda; Board of Directors' meeting agenda for September 17; Executive Committee meeting agenda for September 16; booklet from National Center for Educational Statistics, Mobility in the Teacher Workforce: Findings from the Condition of Education 2005; memo re need for volunteers to assist with Hurricane Katrina relief; proposed timeline and other materials re 2006 Representative Assembly; proposed program for Thomas Hobart dedication on September 26; list of retired part-time employees and hourly wages, January 1, 2004- July 31, 2005; list of NYSUT payments to AFL-CIO Central Labor Councils as of August 2005; article from Washington Post re two former teachers union officials convicted of embezzlement, September 1; memo re NYSUT holiday parties, August 26; request from regional staff director Fred Monaco for contribution of $1500 to Center for Missing and Exploited Children's Ride for Missing Children, January 12
- Officers Meeting 6/14/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  Directory of Board of Directors; materials for AFT Solidarity Fund, NYSUT Solidarity Fund
- Officers Meeting 6/28/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  Memo re membership cards; survey results for start time for board meetings; annual estimated per capita for 2005
- Officers Meeting 6/22/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  Agenda; confidential memo from Office of Counsel to the President re Department of Labor LM-30 Form update and recommended course of action, June 30; Cabinet Meeting notes of May 25; memo re AFT financial support, June 21
- Officers Meeting 6/6/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 85)
- Officers Meeting 6/1/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  Memos re budget reform bills; confidential memo re Political Action Committee appointments; 2005-2006 budget requests for new positions, promotions, and upgrades
- Officers Meeting 5/24/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  Agenda for Executive Committee meeting; confidential memo re Political Action Committee appointments; list of staff requesting to attend QuEST; proposed 2005 nominations for Referred Resolutions Committee; list of officers attendance at NYSUT Regional/Statewide Leadership Conferences, updated 5/11/05
- Officers Retreat April 25-27, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  Retreat agendas; site information
- Officers Meeting 4/19/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 89)
- Officers Meeting 3/8/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  Agenda for Officers' Advisory Committee meeting; agenda for Executive Committee meeting of March 13; Maria Neira's talking points re National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month; confidential legal memo re bylaws of UNITY Caucus
- Officers Meeting 2/22/05, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  Agenda and revised agenda for Board of Trustees meeting of NYSUT Education and Learning Trust; minutes of November 23, 2004, meeting; course outlines for "Multiple Intelligence Strategies" and "Instructional Strategies for the Cooperative Classroom"; memo to Chuck Santelli from Ro Rosen re Sunguard software proposal, February 7, 2005; description of items to be discussed by the board, from Ro Rosen; summary of major provisions of The Schools for New York's Future Act, with school aid chart; Benchmark (NYSUT) Polling Group results of survey of prime voters statewide re New York State representatives and issues, conducted January 31 through February 3, 2005; flyer supporting the UNITY team
- Officers and Associates Meeting 4/12/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Agenda; notes of Officers meeting of March 29, 2005; Forbes article re costly, low-quality retirement plans sold to teachers by AIG-affiliated vendor, April 25, 2005; draft letter to the editor of Forbes from director of NYSUT Benefit Trust re ING-affiliated plan, noting satisfaction with it, April 12, 2005; letter from NYSUT president Ianuzzi to NYSUT members re ING-affiliated Opportunity Plus supplemental retirement savings plan (tax-deferred variable annuity, TDA); information re filing Form LM-30 with Department of Labor
- Officers and Associates Meeting 3/29/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Executive Committee and Board of Directors' meeting agenda for April 7, 2005; notes of Officers meeting of March 15, 2005; list of officers on UNITY Caucus Nominations Committee; Subcommittee on Education Report to the General Conference Committee; Senate and Assembly Higher Education Conference Committee Recommendations; memo to NYSUT officers re request for new legislative representative position, March 28, 2005; Research and Educational Services Staff Planning Session Framework; materials re Regents proposal to increase the passing grade on Regents exams to 65; NYSUT Recommendations re NYS's Implementation of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2005, with cover letter from vice president Maria Neira to deputy commissioner of Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities, March 28, 2005
- Officers and Associates Meeting 3/15/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Officers and Associate Meeting 3/1/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Agenda; notes of Officers meeting of January 25, 2005; draft executive summary of the K-12 Local Presidents' Survey, 2004-05; report of Field & Legal Services, February 28, 2005; summary of NYSUT 2005-06 budget, prepared by the Office of the Secretary-Treasurer; list of executive salaries for 2005-06; memos re retiree health insurance for management and confidential staff, January 15 and February 23, 2005
- Officers and Associates Meeting 1/4/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Agenda; notes from November 23 and December 21, 2004, Officers' Meetings; State Education Department press release, "Eleven Schools Placed on SURR List, 19 Removed in New York City, Yonkers, Buffalo, Syracuse and Hempstead," January 4; draft NYSUT press release, "New SURR List Shows Progress: Teachers Frustrated by State's Inaction," January 4; blast e-mail to media, statement by Randi Weingarten calling SURR news bittersweet, January 4; 2005 Representative Assembly materials, including tentative list of speakers, proposed resolutions; materials re NYSUT member benefits, auto policy; AFT Guidelines for Audit Committees, fall 2003; memo re NYSUT-CWA tentative agreement, with salary steps, January 4
- Officers and Associates Meeting 11/23/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Agenda for Officers' and Associates' meeting, November 23; draft statement of operations for year ended August 31, 2004; Education and Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting agenda, November 23; minutes of September 8 meeting; budget note to Chuck Santelli from Ro (Rosemarie) Rosen of the Education and Learning Trust, October 26; course outline and syllabus for proposed new course, Differentiated Instruction: Improving the ODDS, with cover memo from Ro Rosen, October 27; memo from Ro Rosen re proposed partnership with the Sage Colleges and Concordia College, with attached financial arrangement, November 17; NYSUT Cell Phone Policy (addendum to Travel and Expense Reimbursement Policy), effective 2004
- Officers and Associates Meeting (Canceled) 11/16/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Memo notifying of cancellation
- Officers and Associates Meeting 4/13/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Agenda for Officers' and Associates' meeting of April 13; agenda and notes from Officers' meeting of March 18; agenda and notes of Officers' meeting of April 13; NYUSUT Financial Statements as of February 29, 2004; membership and financial report from Ivan Tiger, April 12; report on attendance of the 2004 Representative Assembly; list of members of task force on future of RAs, revised 4/5/04
- Officers Meeting 3/18/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Agenda; notes of March 2 Officers' meeting; minutes of February 17 Officers' meeting; special order of business, Response to Secretary of Education Paige's "Terrorist" Comments, re Bush administration official's remark that National Education Association was a terrorist organization; New York State Teachers Retirement System Trustee Agreement, April 6, 1992; tentative agenda for 2004 AFT Super Conference Northeast Regional Meeting
- Officers Meeting 3/2/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Agenda; NYSUT letter to AFT re per capita dues from Public Employees Federation, February 20; lists of bargaining units; 2004 Representative Assembly draft general session tentative speakers and program; interim report on security and civil liberties, to AFT officers and Executive council, from Democracy Committee, May 2003
- Officers Meeting 2/17/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Agenda; draft of certified letter to Hudson Valley Community College, severing joint sponsorship agreement between NYSUT Education and Learning Trust and college; memos re per capita dues collection for AFT from Public Employees Federation
- Officers Meeting 1/15/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws, effective April 2003; memo re health insurance for retirees/managers under current NYSUT policy, January 5, 2004; NYSUT special projects budget, 2002-2003
- Officers Meeting 1/6/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Agenda; memo re associate member dues; comparison between Regents proposal and NYSUT Ad Hoc Task Force on School Finance Report; letter requesting sponsorship of Albany Law School Government Law Center's 2004 Warren M. Anderson Legislative Breakfast Seminar Series, December 16, 2003
- Officers and Associates Meeting 9/8/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Agenda; materials re CUNY Professional Staff Congress (PSC) request for financial assistance, September 7; Report of the Task Force on Small and Rural Locals, July 23, 2004; letter from Pauline Kinsella, NYSUT Executive Director of Field and Legal Services, to president of Professional Staff Association re his concern over number of management/confidential positions at NYSUT
- Officers and Associates Meeting 8/2/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Agenda; agendas for Executive Committee and Board of Directors' meetings of August 4; notes from Officers' meeting of June 16; recommended procedures for AFT/Kerry presidential campaign volunteer expense reimbursement; memo re financial statement recording of dues collected for AFT, August 2; correspondence re theft by one of Port Jefferson paraprofessionals co-presidents; confidential draft, NYSUT Personnel Committee Principles re promotions for CWA/PSA/LSA employees, with attached appendix of salary steps
- Officers Retreat June 15-16 2004 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Agenda for retreat; list of issues for retreat; agenda for Officers' and Associates' meeting of June 16; list of Officers' and Associates' meetings for 2004-2005; agenda and notes from Officers' meeting of June 1; Personnel Committee recommended salary adjustments; materials re Fundamental Beliefs to Create a Single State Organization, differences with existing policies of NEA-NY and NYSUT; NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws; handwritten notes
- Officers and Associates Meeting 6/1/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Agenda; agenda and notes from Officers' meeting of May 19; map of 2002-03 NYS School Districts Median Teacher Salary Ranges, with report on classroom teacher salaries; anonymous letter to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re "antics" of president (?) of Syracuse Teachers Association, May 17; memo re content management/portal expenditure, June 1; estimated costs associated with attending NYS AFL-CIO Constitutional Convention, August 8-10, 2004; emerging leader accomplishments
- Officers and Associates Meeting 5/19/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Agendas for May 19 and 20 meetings; working 2004-05 salary schedule; memo to Tom Hobart re 2004-2005 budget, May 10; handwritten notes from May 11 budget meeting; typed notes from 5/11 budget meeting with officers; brochure from the Eleanor Roosevelt Center at Val-Kill (Hyde Park, NY), with memo re NYSUT contribution, May 13; Peter D. Hart Research Associates survey results re public opinion of state of education, taxes, perception of teachers, April/May 2004; memo from NYSUT legal counsel re Appellate Division decision re duty to fairly represent retirees in Baker et al. v. Hoosick Falls Central School District et al., recommending settlement, May 17
- Officers and Associates Meeting 5/19/04 2005 Budget Draft, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  NYSUT 2004-2005 Budget officers' presentation, June 1, 2004; NYSUT Building Corporation Annual Report, June 10, 2004; budget drafts; summary of major changes version #1 to version #2; major equipment request schedule; list of special projects; committee budget lines; management/confidential salary adjustments per 5/11/04 Officers' Meeting; notes from 5/11 budget meeting with officers (accounting notes as of 5/19); additional areas to consider for potential cost containment
- Officers Meeting 4/26/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Agenda; proposed new procedure for Associate Member Program, effective September 1, 2004; agenda and notes of Officers' meeting of April 13; memo from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to Board of Directors re NEA-NY convention's approval of "sanitized" unity resolution that left unresolved a list of issues that had traditionally divided NYSUT and NEA, April 26, 2005
- Officers Retreat October 19-20, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Confidential draft notes
- Officers and Associates Meeting 12/21/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting, January 12, 2005; memo re AFT financial support, with attached Rationale for the Continuance of AFT Technology Support in New York, November 12; memo to officers re private higher education faculty Associate Membership Program, December 15; NYSU travel and expense reimbursement policy, effective 2004; policy sheet re press releases; list of possible 2005 Representative Assembly Resolutions Committee chairs and vice chairs, December 21; materials re charter school test data, December 20
- Officers Meeting 12/07/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Agenda; summary sheet, 2005 NYSUT Campaign and Election Procedures; materials from 2004 NYSUT Board retreat, October 29-31; list of recipients of Albert Shanker Award for Distinguished Service; NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws, effective March 2004; Davis Vision/Wal-mart Update, outlining options for possible switch from optical provider who distributed at Wal-Mart, with responses to informal Request for Information
- Officers Meeting 11/23/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Agenda; proposed management meeting structure; unsupportive letter to AFT president ED McElroy from NEA president Reg Weaver re possible merger/affiliation arrangement, November 18, 2004; officer Transition Policy after a Successor is Elected and Installed, 11/23/04
- Officers and Associates Meeting 11/02/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Memo re meeting time with "cancelled" notation
- New Officers Gathering 10/8/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  Memos re meeting time
- Officers and Associates Meeting 10/5/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Agenda; agenda for Administrative Committee meeting; presentation sheets re new LM-2 reporting requirements
- Officers Meeting 10/03/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Agenda; NYSUT Retiree Fund 2005-05 Budget; job description for retiree services consultant; related materials; memo re Education Summit 2005; memo from Maria Neira re gaps in committee appointments, with spreadsheet; memo re miscellaneous headquarters items, re Sandra Feldman memorial, Founders' Room, September 30; memo from NYSUT general counsel James Sandner, recommending declining to represent case of probationary teacher, now resigned, charged with several counts of sexual misconduct with a child, September 27; letter from Greenburgh Eleven Federation of Teachers to NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi
- Officers Meeting 9/29/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  Memo confirming meeting date; notes form Officers' meeting of September 8
- Opportunity Plus see ING Life Insurance
- Para Festival (UFT) 2/12/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Letter to Maria Neira inviting her to awards ceremony honoring outstanding paraprofessionals
- Paras New Certification Requirements 2002-2005 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Letter from NYSUT Education and Learning Trust re Paraprofessional Education Program: Pathway to a Career in Education, August 10, 2005, with attached document; text of bill introduced by Rep. Jose Serrano (D-NY), Paraprofessionals in the Classroom Act of 2005, with fax cover from congressional office, January 10, 2005, and memo to Maria Neira summarizing legislation, February 8, 2005; UFT newsletter, ParaScope, fall 2004; NYSUT Information Bulletin re new certification requirements for teaching assistants, January 2003; text of Schools for New York's Future Act; U.S. Department of Education Draft Non-Regulatory Guidance re Title I Paraprofessionals under No Child Left Behind, November 15, 2002
- Paraprofessionals see AFT Paraprofessionals and School-Related Personnel Conference
- Parent-Teacher Conferences see Radio Ad
- Personnel Committee Meeting and Materials, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Memo re meeting, noting planned review of recommendations for promotions, with guidelines, May 3, 2005
- Policy/ PR Campaign Meeting 12/12/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  List of Policy Council planned meetings for 2005-2006, with major topics to be discussed; message from Maria Neira to Policy Council members on listserv; Procedure for Expiring Resolutions; memo to Research and Educational Services managers from Chuck Santelli re "to-do" list from Executive Council and Board of Directors meetings, 12/12/05
- NYSUT Policy Council Members, 2005-2008 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  List of members with e-mail and street addresses, district affiliations
- NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 10/12/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  Memo re 2005-06 Policy Council meetings; memo re topics for discussion at October 12 meeting. See also AFT Teachers Program and Policy Council
- NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 1/12/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Agenda; list of attendees; list of those not attending or responding; draft 2004- 05 K-12 Local Presidents' Survey Summary; survey overview; survey possible discussion points; materials from State Education Department re assessment review and action on student performance, January 6; related memos
- NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 11/8/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  Agenda; list of upcoming meetings; memo from Maria Neira re State Education Department's latest middle-level proposal, September 24, 2004; letter from Neira to Chancellor Bennett, expressing concern over latest middle-level proposal, October 28, 2004; related materials; questions on grades 3-8 standards & assessments; list of Policy Council members; flowchart, New York State Education Department Examination Development Process; NYSUT Research and Educational Services report, "Assessments in New York State: List of tests students in New York face as they progress from kindergarten through public higher education," October 2004; presentation sheets, Current Issues and Future Directions for Testing, Assessment and Accountability, by Howard J. Goldsmith, coordinator of operations, NYSED Office of State Assessment; description of State Education Department Mathematics Standards Committee; list of contract expirations, 2002-04; draft document re alternative compensation plans; handwritten notes
- NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 4/21/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  Agenda; notes from January 7, 2004, meeting; report of the First Vice President, for Executive Committee, April 15; materials re middle-level options; NYSUT report, Explosion of Excellence: The education revolution no one is talking about, March 2004; state fiscal policy recommendations, "There's Still a Better Choice," by NYSUT Committee of 100; handwritten notes
- Policy Issues Ann Cook Meeting 01/7/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  Memos arranging a meeting; handwritten notes
- Post-Election Summary 11/11/04, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  Memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to NYSUT Board of Directors, officers, and staff, analyzing results of presidential, congressional, and state legislative races, efforts of NYSUT volunteers, with attached NYSUT flyers for Democratic presidential candidate John Kerry. See also Kerry
- Practitioners Advisory Panel January-February 2003 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  List of assessment committee members; summary of initial meeting, February 3; State Education Department Information for Practitioners' Advisory Panel Discussion, with handwritten notations
- Practitioners Panel on Testing 3/12/03, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  Summary of January 30, 2003, meeting; letter to NYSUT first vice president Antonia Cortese from State Education Department assistant commissioner, describing the advisory panel's assignment, January 3, 2003; NYSUT Feedback Form for Comments Regarding SED's Practitioners' Advisory Panel on Grades 3-8 Testing, with cover letter from NYSUT vice president Cortese to participant, February 10, 2003; filled-out form from another participant; Request for Proposal from State Education Department for State Assessment in Elementary and Intermediate (Middle) Level English Language Arts and Mathematics (scoring proposals); handwritten notes
- Professional Development Educational Issues: Video Conference 5/26, 5/31, 6/01 2005 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  NYSUT Educational Services list of topics and issues for videoconference briefing to NYSUT regional offices, May 26, 31, and June 1, 2005; revised announcement, Critical Issues Briefing: Educational Issues Videoconference
- Professional Development Meeting 9/23/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  Memos arranging a time for the meeting; State Education Department document to superintendents of selected school districts re Title IIA and Professional Development Plan Monitoring, September 28, 2004; paper, School Variation and Systemic Instructional Improvement in Community School District #2, New York City, by Richard F. Elmore and Deanna Burney, October 1997; earlier version, August 1997
- Professional Standards and Practices Board for Teaching (PSPB) Meetings 9/22/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  Agenda for breakfast meeting; agenda for full day's meeting; list of attendees; list of issues re mentoring; comparison of the Teaching Commission report recommendations and NYS initiatives to date (draft) re improving state licensing and certification requirements, more authority to principals; draft proposal re performance assessment of teaching skills, 9/12
- PSPB March 23-24, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  Materials re legislative (lobbying) visits
- PSPB 6/2/05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 47)